lungusa.org 2019-12-01

# Privacy Policy | American Lung Association

American Lung Association has created this Privacy Policy to explain why we collect particular information and how we will protect your personal privacy within our website. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the websites located at the URLs lung.org and action.lung.org.

In order to fully understand your rights we encourage you to read this Privacy Policy as well as our [Terms of Use](https://www.lung.org/about-us/terms-of-use.html). American Lung Association reserves the right at any time and without notice to change this Privacy Policy simply by posting such changes on our Site. Any such change will be effective immediately upon posting.

  1. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, this Privacy Policy notifies you of;
  2. What personally identifiable information of yours is collected through the Site;
  3. Who collects such information;
  4. How such information is used;
  5. With whom your information may be shared;
  6. What choices you have regarding collection, use and distribution of your information;
  7. What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control;
  8. How you can correct any inaccuracies in your information.

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to American Lung Association by sending an email to [webmaster@lung.org](mailto:webmaster@lung.org?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Questions). Please reference this Privacy Policy in your subject line.

**What Information We Collect and How We Use That  Information:**  
Our registration forms require users to give us contact information that may include name, email address, format preference (HTML vs. Text), address, interests, and similar information. In the event that an online form has fees and/or donations associated, we may request credit card information for the purpose of processing the transaction. We do not request or store sensitive information from our visitors, such as social security numbers.

We may share some information about you with partners for marketing purposes. The American Lung Association may also rent or exchange your personal information with other organizations, and we may also use your personal information and browsing history to contact you for communications and marketing purposes.

The Lung Association respects the privacy of its financial supporters and website visitors, as such, would be pleased to exclude you from its list rental and exchange program. Please inform us if this is your desire at [lung.org/consumerchoice](https://www.lung.org/get-involved/consumer-choice-menu/consumer-choice-menu.html).

If you want to unsubscribe from marketing email and postal mail communications, go to [lung.org/consumerchoice](https://www.lung.org/consumerchoice) and select your preferences.

**Social:**  
Information from social networking sites (such as Facebook and Twitter). We collect information from social media activity, including likes, shares and tweets about our content on social networking sites. Where you sign in to lung.org using social network credentials, such as a Facebook log-in, you grant permission to the social network to share your user details.

**Internet Protocol Address:**  
We collect an IP address from all visitors to our Site. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. We use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Site, analyze trends, track user's movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use in order for us to improve the site, and deliver customized, personalized content.

**Use of "Cookies":**  
Our Site may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our Site. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites transfer to the computer that is browsing that website and are used for record-keeping purposes at many websites. Use of cookies makes web-surfing easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences regarding your use of the particular website and to make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard.  We and our partners may use cookies and other tracking technologies to collect information for our own marketing purposes and to support other marketers.

If you would like to opt-out of targeted advertising from the broader digital marketing community, please visit the opt-out page of the The Network Advertising Initiative (NAI):

http://optout.networkadvertising.org/

Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our Site will not function properly when you view them.

**Security:**  
All information provided to American Lung Association is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. We also protect account information by placing it on a secure portion of our Site that is only accessible by certain qualified employees of American Lung Association. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet is 100% secure. While we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of such information.

**Tell-A-Friend:**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our Site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. American Lung Association will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the Site. American Lung Association stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

**Other Websites:**  
Our Site contains links to other websites and/or third party API integrations. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which American Lung Association has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may be different than ours.

**How We Respond to "Do Not Track" Signals:**  
Our website does not respond to web browser "Do No Track" signals.

**Contacting the website:**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Site, or your dealings with this Site, you can send an email to: [webmaster@lung.org](mailto:webmaster@lung.org?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20%20Questions).

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act):**  
We do not knowingly request or collect information from any person under 13 years of age without parental consent. If you believe that your child has submitted personal information without your consent and you would like this info restricted or removed, please contact [webmaster@lung.org](mailto:webmaster@lung.org?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20%20Questions).

**Online Behavioral Advertising (OBA) Compliance**  
We may also participate in interest-based advertising using similar technology. This means that you may see advertising on our website tailored to how you browse or shop, or you may see advertising for the Lung Association on other websites based on your browsing behavior across websites. Some websites where we may advertise belong to ad networks that use your web browsing history to choose which ads to display on their network websites; these ads include advertising for the Lung Association, but no personal information about you is shared with those third party ad networks. Other websites where you see our ads, such as Facebook, may use interest preferences that you have chosen on those sites, as well as registration and other information about you, to choose which ads to display to you. Some internet browsers, websites such as Facebook and mobile devices offer opt-outs for interest-based advertising. Please refer to the website that you are visiting, your browser and/or your device settings for additional information.
